Guide to the Herbert Hoeger Gay Porn Library MSS.582
Fales Library and Special Collections
Herbert Hoeger Gay Porn Library
1967-1998, undated
Fales Library and Special Collections
Hoeger, Herbert, 1924-2014
Mackintosh, Jane
MSS.582
1.50 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes.
Herbert Hoeger (1924-2014) was born in the Czech Republic in an area formerly recognized as Austria. He was drafted into the German Army during World War II, was captured and stayed a POW until he was discharged in 1946. Hoeger immigrated to the United States in 1957, eventually becoming a U.S. citizen. He lived in New York City and Warrensburg, New York, working as a lab technician for a dairy and a model for print ads. The Herbert Hoeger Gay Porn Library is a small collection of Hoeger's gay erotic novels and publications dating from the late 1960s through the 1970s, as well as a small number of illustrated instructional booklets on homosexuality and sexual education.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jane MacKintosh, April 2018; the accession number associated with this gift is 2019.042.
Appraisal
In August 2019, curator evaluated the publication Boystown, decided it was outside the institution's collecting scope, and removed it from the collection.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged at the item-level in alphabetical order by title.
Biographical Note
Herbert Hoeger (1924-2014) was born in the Czech Republic in an area previously identified as Austria. In 1942, he was drafted into the German Army, captured by the U.S., then placed in various POW camps located in Europe and the United States. He was discharged from the army in 1946, attended college in Vienna, and immigrated to the United States in 1957. He became a U.S. citizen in 1978. Hoeger lived mostly in New York City and Warrensburg, New York. He worked as a lab technician for a dairy and was a model for print ads.
Scope and Contents
The Herbert Hoeger Gay Porn Library is a small collection of gay erotic novels and publications dating from the late 1960s through the 1970s, and also includes a small number of illustrated instructional booklets on homosexuality and sexual education.
Gay erotica.; Gay men in literature.; Gay men -- Sexual behavior -- United States; Sex instruction -- United States; Gay erotic stories, American; Homosexuality -- United States.; Sexual health; Novels.; Serial publications.; Mackintosh, Jane
- 7 in a Barn, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Another Room--Another Brother, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Boys in the Band, #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bunkhouse Boy, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- A Case Study: Headhunters, Volume 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Come Quick!, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Compulsive Homosexuality in the Married Man, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Concentration of Hans, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Copsucker, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Die Männer Mit Dem Rosa Winkel, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- First Hand Experiences for Loving Men, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Friction, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Gay Boys, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Gloryhole Hustler, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Guidebook to Sexual Positions Between Consenting Adults, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Hairport, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Handjobs Anthology, Volumes 1-3, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- Homo '69, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Homosexual Sexuality, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Meat My Buddy, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- The Mustee, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- One to Share..., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Oral Genital Activity, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- The Players, No. 1, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Plug-In Stud!, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Sex Arena, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Silent Men, #1, #3, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- The Young Homosexual, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)